<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Michael J. Mitchell, Ph.D.</title>
    <link>http://michaeljmitchell.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Michael J. Mitchell, Ph.D.</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 21 Jan 2017 17:53:46 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://michaeljmitchell.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>http://michaeljmitchell.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jan 2017 17:53:46 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://michaeljmitchell.com/about/</guid>
      <description>I am a Sr. Engineer and Technical Lead of the Customer Experience (CX) Lab at T-Mobile. Current R&amp;amp;D includes optimization of telemetry collection, aggregation, visualization, monitoring, and anomaly detection platforms as well as modernizing CI/CD/CT infrastructure using open source software and modern DevOps design patterns. Since I joined the lab in 2015, I have also been driving new mobile LTE security research initiatives, prototyping new mobile and IoT product concepts, and developing synthetic user experience automation and analytic tools.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>http://michaeljmitchell.com/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jan 2017 17:53:46 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://michaeljmitchell.com/publications/</guid>
      <description>Cashtags: Protecting The Input And Display Of Sensitive Data. Michael Mitchell, An-I Andy Wang, and Peter Reiher. Proceedings of the 24th USENIX Security Symposium, 2015. (Supersedes Technical Report TR-141209). [PDF]
Cashtags: Protecting The Input And Display Of Sensitive Data. Michael Mitchell. Doctoral Dissertation, Department of Computer Science, Florida State University, 2015. [PDF]
Mobile Usage Patterns and Privacy Implications. Michael Mitchell, Ratnesh Patidar, Manik Saini, Parteek Singh, An-I Andy Wang, and Peter Reiher.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>